<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidymodels on Tarana-Fundamentals of Data Analystics</title>
    <link>/categories/tidymodels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidymodels on Tarana-Fundamentals of Data Analystics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/tidymodels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final Project: Business Analysis</title>
      <link>/2021/08/07/final-project-business-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/08/07/final-project-business-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the financial benefit of the project
This project would benefit credit card providers by detecting customers who have the potential of missing their credit card payments. Although this is not an unfamiliar situation for these institutions, it affects their revenue every year by making them prosecute these clients. This project gives you two options two avoid these customers based on two categories of information you already have!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resampling method : Cross Validation &amp; Bootstrap</title>
      <link>/2021/07/29/resampling-method-cross-validation-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/07/29/resampling-method-cross-validation-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>To explore the resampling techniques here the professors diamond ring data and bank data are used consecutively,in order to estimate the test error rates that result from fitting linear and logistic models on these two data sets.
## # A tibble: 6 x 9 ## Carat Colour Clarity Cut Certification Polish Symmetry Price Wholesaler ## &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; ## 1 0.92 I SI2 G AGS V V 3000 1 ## 2 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree based Method: Random Forest</title>
      <link>/2021/07/29/tree-based-method-random-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/07/29/tree-based-method-random-forest/</guid>
      <description>Overview To implement Random Forest method, the bank data set is used here, on which dataset, the classification technique is used earlier. As we know, Random Forest being one of the supervised machine learning, provides more flexibility and accuracy of the model over decision trees adding extra randomness.
In Random Forests the idea is to decorrelate the several trees which are generated by the different bootstrapped samples from training Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification models : Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>/2021/07/15/classification-models-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/07/15/classification-models-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>Summary of Data The data is related with direct marketing campaigns of a Portuguese banking institution. The marketing campaigns were based on phone calls. To identify whether a customer would subscribe the bank term deposit or not, most of the time more than one contact to the same customer was required. Now,the information of a customers age, job, marital, education, default, balance, housing, loan, contact along side the data of day, month, duration, campaign, previous days, previous, previous outcome are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>/2021/06/21/final-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/06/21/final-project/</guid>
      <description>Data Analysis to fit Linear Regression Model: This is an exploratory data analysis report to fit the simple Linear Regression Model. This report concerns a dataset about Life Expectancy.
 Categorical and numerical explanatory variables analysis: For finding whether there is any relation between the dataset or not, I have done some basic analysis to find the dependent and independent variables.From these analysis, the variable, Life Expectancy has came out as dependent variable(y) as it is effected by other predictive variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiting and Interpreting Models</title>
      <link>/2021/06/15/fiting-and-interpreting-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/06/15/fiting-and-interpreting-models/</guid>
      <description>Import Libraries  # Models with numerical explanatory variables  Data: Paris Paintings pp &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;paris-paintings.csv&amp;quot;, na = c(&amp;quot;n/a&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;NA&amp;quot;))  Number of observations: 3393 Number of variables: 61   Goal: Predict height from width ## Step 1: Specify model
## Linear Regression Model Specification (regression)  Step 2: Set model fittung “engine” linear_reg() %&amp;gt;% set_engine(&amp;quot;lm&amp;quot;) #linear model  Step 3: Fit model and estimate parameters ## # A tibble: 2 x 5 ## term estimate std.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
